# **Matheus Bordin Marchi**

# **Data Analyst**

© Florianopolis/SC, Brazil · &+55 (48) 98500 2608 · □mbordinmarchi@gmail.com · imlinkedin.com/in/mbordinmarchi

Portfolio Website: Case study - Cyclistic bikes - Analysis of a bike-sharing company data using *R* 

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY** –

Versatile and dedicated individual with a Master's and a PhD in Mathematics, willing to use mathematical expertise, analytical thinking and logic skills obtained during the last 13 years in real business problems as a data analyst. Excellent understanding and proficiency in various data analysis platforms, including *SQL*, *Excel*, *Tableau*, and *R*. Entry-level data analytics professional, recently completed the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate. Goal and detail-oriented, focused and quick learner. Full professional proficiency in *English* and reading proficiency in *French*.

### **SKILLS**

• SQL • Excel (VLookup, Conditional Formatting, Pivot Tables)

• R (dplyr, tidyr, lubridate, ggplot2)

- Tableau
- Problem Solving
- Research and Presentation
- Analytical Thinking

### **EDUCATION** -

# **Postdoctoral in Pure and Applied Mathematics**

Federal University of Santa Catarina, Florianopolis/SC, Brazil

### **PhD in Pure and Applied Mathematics**

2018 - 2022

Dec 2022 - Present

Federal University of Santa Catarina, Florianopolis/SC, Brazil

### **Master of Science in Pure and Applied Mathematics**

Federal University of Santa Catarina, Florianopolis/SC, Brazil

# 2010 - 2015

2016 - 2018

### **Bachelor of Science in Mathematics**

Federal University of Santa Maria, Santa Maria/RS, Brazil with an exchange period at Lakehead University, Thunder Bay/ON, Canada

- Selected as one of 7,000 participants nationwide in 2013 for the 16-months Science without Borders scholarship program funded by the Brazilian government for high-achieving talent based on leadership potential and academic success.
- Developed skills in leadership, versatility, ability to relate, communicate, and English proficiency.

### **EXPERIENCE** -

### **Math Content Translator freelancer (remote)**

Jul 2022 - Jan 2023

Photomath Inc., San Mateo/CA, USA

Helped the company translate their learning mobile app to make it available in the Brazilian market.

### **Mathematics Tutoring with Pedagogical Support**

Oct 2020 - Dec 2021

Federal University of Santa Catarina, Florianopolis/SC, Brazil

- Provided daily personalized support to undergraduate students with diverse backgrounds in the tutoring program, resulting in a significant decrease in the number of students dropping the course by the end of the semester.
- Conducted surveys and compiled data for reports. Maintained a database of 400 students.
- Helped increase retention rates by an average of 18% compared to previous years.

## CERTIFICATION

## **Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate**

Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

- · Completed extensive 6 months job-ready Google Career Certificate training.
- Demonstrated hands-on experience with data cleaning, data visualization, project management, interpreting and communicating data analytics findings. Confidence in transforming complex data into actionable and clear insights.
- Fluency in programming languages used for data analysis and a solid understanding of databases.